<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.deutschestextarchiv.de/basisformat.rng"
type="application/xml"
schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="dtabf">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">About us</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>
                    <orgName>Institut für die Geschichte der deutschen Juden</orgName>
                    <email>redaktion@juedische-geschichte-online.net</email>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>Beim Schlump 83, 20144 Hamburg</addrLine>
                    </address>
                </publisher>
                <pubPlace>Hamburg</pubPlace>
                <date type="publication">2023-09-27</date>
                <!--
                <availability>
                    <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/de/">
                        <p>Dieser Text basiert auf den <ref target="http://www.deutschestextarchiv.de/doku/nutzungsbedingungen">Nutzungsbestimmungen des Deutschen Textarchivs</ref> und darf gemäß den Bestimmungen der <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/de/">CC-BY-NC 3.0</ref> für nicht-kommerzielle Zwecke in jedwedem Format oder Medium vervielfältigt und weiterverbreitet werden. </p>
                    </licence>
                </availability>
                -->
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p/>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="eng">English</language>
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div n="3">
                <head>Team</head>
                <lb/>

                <p><hi rendition="#b">PD Dr. Andreas Brämer (IGdJ, project leader)</hi>
                    <lb/> Andreas Brämer is deputy director at the IGdJ. He studied at the
                    University of Jewish Studies Heidelberg and at the Hebrew University in
                    Jerusalem. He received his doctorate in Jewish Studies from the Free University
                    of Berlin – with a dissertation on Rabbi Zacharias Frankel. Before Andreas
                    Brämer transferred to the Institute for the History of the German Jews in 1997,
                    he worked as an academic staff member at the Hochschule für Jüdische Studien and
                    at the Gesamthochschule Duisburg. Since his habilitation in 2006, he has also
                    taught as a private lecturer (adjunct professor) in the Department of History at
                    the University of Hamburg. Andreas Brämer is a member of the board of the <ref
                        target="http://wag-leobaeck.de/">Wissenschaftliche Arbeitsgemeinschaft of
                        the Leo Baeck Institute</ref> and chairman of the <ref
                        target="https://gegj.de/">Gesellschaft zur Erforschung der Geschichte der
                        Juden e. V.</ref> He is also a member of the advisory board of the <ref
                        target="https://www.maimonides-centre.uni-hamburg.de/">Maimonides Centre for
                        Advanced Studies – Jewish Scepticism</ref> at the University of Hamburg and
                    a member of the advisory board of the <ref
                        target="https://www.leobaeck.co.uk/the-lbi-year-book-2">Leo Baeck Institute
                        Yearbook</ref>. </p>

                <p><hi rendition="#b">PD Dr.-Ing. habil. Ulrich Knufinke (Bet Tfila – Research Unit,
                        project leader)</hi>
                    <lb/> Ulrich Knufinke is a research associate at the Lower Saxony State Office
                    for the Preservation of Historical Monuments, where his responsibilities in the
                    department for the preservation of historical buildings and art include the
                    coordination of research projects. He studied architecture and German language
                    and literature at the Technical University of Braunschweig, where he received
                    his doctorate in 2005. In 2014, he completed his habilitation at the University
                    of Stuttgart. In addition to his work at the NLD, Knufinke currently teaches as
                    a private lecturer at the TU Braunschweig, where he is the scientific director
                    of the <ref target="http://www.bet-tfila.org/">Bet Tfila – Research Unit for
                        Jewish Architecture in Europe</ref>.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi rendition="#b">Dr. Sonja Dickow-Rotter (IGdJ, project staff)</hi>
                    <lb/> Sonja Dickow-Rotter is an academic staff member at the IGdJ since 2019 and
                    initially a project staff member of the digital source edition <ref
                        target="https://keydocuments.net/">Key Documents of German-Jewish
                        History</ref>. In this context, she also conceptualized and implemented
                    online exhibitions as well as other digital formats. Sonja Dickow-Rotter studied
                    literature and cultural anthropology at the University of Hamburg. After
                    receiving her master’s degree, she worked as an academic staff member at the
                    Walter A. Berendsohn Research Center for Exile Literature. Sonja Dickow-Rotter
                    wrote her doctoral dissertation on literary configurations of house and home in
                    contemporary Jewish literatures. Her comparative dissertation, which was awarded
                    the University of Hamburg's Joseph Carlebach Prize in 2021, was written at the
                    University of Hamburg and at the Hebrew University of Jerusalem. Sonja
                    Dickow-Rotter is an alumna of the Ernst Ludwig Ehrlich Scholarship Fund. </p>
                <p>
                    <hi rendition="#b">Dipl.- Ing. Mirko Przystawik (Bet Tfila – Research Unit,
                        project staff)</hi>
                    <lb/> Mirko Przystawik studied architecture at the Technische Universität
                    Braunschweig and has been working as architectural historian since 2005: First,
                    he served as a research associate at the Institute for the History of
                    Architecture and Urban Development, Department of Architectural History, and
                    since 2007 at the Bet Tfila – Research Unit there. Parallel to this, he assumed
                    his work at the IGdJ as an academic staff member in 2019. In various projects,
                    he has addressed his research focus – modern Jewish architecture and material
                    culture as well as Jewish topography, for example in the project <hi
                        rendition="#i">“Jüdische Reform und Architektur: Die ‘Erfindung’ der
                        Reformsynagoge im heutigen Land Niedersachsen und ihre weltweite Verbreitung
                        im 19. Jahrhundert”</hi> (Jewish Reform and Architecture: The ‘Invention’ of
                    the Reform Synagogue in the Present-Day State of Lower Saxony and its Worldwide
                    Dissemination in the Nineteenth Century), 2009–2012, Bet Tfila – Research Unit
                    and IGdJ. His current project at Bet Tfila – Research Unit is titled <hi
                        rendition="#i"><ref target="http://bet-tfila.org/de/r-topographien.html"
                            >“Niedersachsen – Eine jüdische Topographie”</ref></hi> (Lower Saxony –
                    A Jewish Topography). In previous projects, he did research on the Jewish rural
                    community in Hornburg and Torah arks in German-speaking regions. </p>
            </div>
            <!--
            <div n="3">
                <head>Advisory Board</head><lb/>
                <list>
                    <item></item>
                </list>
            </div>
            <div n="3">
                <head>Sponsors and Partners</head><lb/>
                <p>The <ref target="https://www.volkswagenstiftung.de/en">Volkswagen Foundation</ref> has been funding the realization of the hybrid publication project since 2023.</p>
            </div>
            -->
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
